[BATGAP theme music playing]
Darryl Anka (Bashar)
July 14, 2014
Buddha at the Gas Pump Interview
Welcome to Buddha at the Gas Pump.
My name is Rick Archer and my guest today
is Darryl Anka, who channels an entity known
as Bashar.
Well first of all, welcome Darryl thanks for
doing this.
Thank you Rick, my pleasure.
Thank you for having me, I really appreciate
it.
Yeah well this is gonna be fun.
Those who have been watching this show for
some time know that I have a fairly eclectic
understanding, or orientation, towards spirituality.
I feel that the universe is far more vast
and diverse, and complex and mysterious than
most of us realize, and that it’s all pervaded
by Divine intelligence, and that Divine intelligence
has a lot of tricks up it’s sleeve [chuckles].
You know, a lot of different ways of enabling
people to more fully realize that deep reality.
So I don’t rule out much of anything as
a valid spiritual path, and I think that people
choose the paths which they feel the most
resonance or affinity, and that’s cool with
me.
So I feel that the purpose of this show is
to expose people to a variety of teachers
and teachings and paths and spiritual orientations,
and let them use their own judgment as to
what works for them.
So I say that as, you know, a little bit of
an introduction because I know that some of
my audience will think, “Oh, channeling,
aliens and all this stuff.
What does this have to do?– I’m into Vedanta.”
And so I’d say, great.
Enjoy Vedanta but Vedanta isn’t the only
game in town.
And if you happen to resonate with what we’re
going to talk about today, and I’m sure
many of you will, then that’s good.
And if you don’t, then I’ll do another
one next week on a different topic [both laughing].
So Darryl, one thing that when I was listening
to your various recordings of Bashar, there’s
one in which he distinguished between, I believe
it was, skepticism and cynicism.
Yes.
Yeah, I like that one, and correct me if I’m
wrong, but he defined skepticism as a sort
of a healthy, open-minded inquisitiveness,
which you’re free to ask questions that
may arise, but you keep an open mind and you’re
willing to revise your perspective if new
evidence is presented.
Whereas cynicism is more like a rigidity,
or a closed-mindedness, where you feel like
you’ve got it all figured out, and you reject
evidence that clashes with your world-view
as being kooky or erroneous, or fallacious,
or whatever.
Yes.
So by that definition, I would consider myself
a skeptic - and it’s sort of a complimentary
term - and I’ll probably be asking some
questions that may seem skeptical, but they’re
asked in all respect and appreciation for
what you do.
Yeah, that’s fine.
Yeah, they may be questions that people we’re
talking to have in their own minds, so we
want to cover them.
So with that introduction, I think this interview
will probably breakdown into two main sections,
and there may be sort of, inter-mixture between
the two sections, but one will be about your
life.
You know, who you are and how you got into
this, and how that whole thing unfolded.
And the other is about Bashar himself and
the knowledge that he is bringing forth.
And so those two are intertwined but somewhat
separate.
So let’s start with the first one first.
As I understand it, you’ve been doing this
for decades now.
30 years.
30 years, yeah, long time.
I know you’ve covered this in other interviews;
there was a great interview on something called
‘Waking Universe’.
I really appreciated that one, that guy did
a good job.
But since the people listening to this will
probably not have listened to that, let’s
cover some of the same ground, and maybe I’ll
ask some different questions.
Sure, absolutely.
So let’s start by just, how did this whole
thing start?
Well, for me it began back in 1973.
I actually had two, very close, broad daylight
UFO sightings here in Los Angeles.
First time, about 150 feet away, the second
time, only about 70 feet away.
Both times it was an equilateral, black, triangular
ship - about 20 or 30 feet on each side.
Now fortunately I had witnesses with me both
times, so I knew I had some collaboration
and some corroboration in that experience
– in both those experiences.
But it was those UFO experiences that started
me investigating what’s this all about?
Because now I’d seen something like that,
I knew that the world wasn’t exactly as
I had been taught it was, and I needed to
find out what was going on.
So in that investigation in the following
years – of course back then there weren’t
a lot of books on a lot of metaphysical subjects.
So you kind of walk into a bookstore looking
for UFO books and books on psychic functioning
or channeling, or things like that, would
all be on the same one shelf in the back of
the store.
So I just kind of went down the line and picked
up on these different books, and tried to
ascertain if one had anything to do with another.
I became familiar with channeling through
the Seth material from Jane Roberts, and I
found it to be…
Hang on just one second before you proceed.
About the UFOs, Los Angeles is a populous
place.
I mean, was this broad daylight, did you say?
Both of them were in broad daylight, yes.
I was on the freeway the first time.
We were actually looking around to see if
anyone else in any of the other cars, while
we were driving, were looking up at this thing.
Everyone in my car saw it, but I couldn’t
tell if anyone else was looking up and seeing
this thing.
It was hovering just above and outside of
this hotel, which was maybe about 12 stories
tall.
And it didn’t make the news or anything?
Well not that I was aware of, although I have
subsequently seen more and more reports of
triangular UFOs since that time.
But I think it took about 2 or 3 years after
my sighting before I actually heard of another
report of a triangular UFO.
They seem to be pretty rare back then; now
they seem to be more and more common.
Ok.
Did you have any spiritual or esoteric tendencies
before this, or was that the catalyst that
got you going?
Not really.
That was the really the catalyst.
I mean my family had raised me Catholic.
You know,
I didn’t really resonate with the idea of
religion in that sense; it was just kind of
surreal to me.
And so no, I didn’t really have any leanings
in any particular spiritual direction, but
this really ignited my curiosity about what
was going on.
Ok, good.
And so later on we’ll talk a lot more about
the UFO phenomenon and all that.
Sure.
But you were about to talk about your exploration
and you mentioned you stumbled upon the Seth
material – Jane Roberts.
Yes, yes, and so that gave me some degree
of introduction to the idea of channeling.
And 10 years after the UFO sighting, I was
actually introduced to a channel who was holding
seminars at the time.
And I went to listen to the information coming
through that channel, and after a few months
I thought, it’s interesting information,
it seems to be constructive, it seems to have
the capacity to help people make positive
and constructive choices in their lives.
Now eventually, that entity offered to teach
a channeling class.
I went into the class, not because I thought
I was going to become a channel; I was just
trying to further my research, ‘cause I
didn’t understand how channeling could be
taught to someone.
My understanding at that point, was that it
was just sort of something that happened to
you out of the blue.
But in the class, which was basically a series
of guided meditations to put you in touch
with whatever you wanted to get in touch with,
be it more creativity, your own higher mind,
or you know, whatever, I received what I can
only describe as a telepathic hit.
And in that one instant, an actual memory
came back of having made an agreement of doing
this channeling with Bashar, in this life.
In that instant I understood the UFO had been
shown to me on purpose, to get me to start
doing the research I was doing so I would
be ready by the time it came time to do the
channeling.
And the information in my head was, “Now
that you know you made this agreement, now
you know it’s time to begin.
Is this something you would still like to
do?”
So this is an agreement that you made before
your birth?
Yes.
And so maybe that’s why the other people
on the freeway didn’t see the UFO, because
it was really meant for you.
And maybe they couldn’t isolate out the
other people in your car [chuckling].
And I’ve heard this happen many times from
other people who’ve reported UFOs.
Sometimes they’ll be standing around a group
of people, and only 1 or 2 people in the group
will actually be able to see the UFO.
So they may have a way of tuning the frequency
to a particular person and making themselves
essentially invisible to anyone who’s not
on that wavelength.
Hmm.
Maybe the people in your car were somewhat
like-minded, you know, more open-minded, higher
consciousness kind of people, or something.
Somewhat, …Sure, well you know, like attracts
like.
They were my brother, my sister, a very, very
close friend of mine and her brother.
So in a sense we were all family.
Ok good.
So you got this hit.
You realized, “Ooh, I had made an agreement
to do this,” and continue.
Yeah, so for a little bit I thought, “Ok,
maybe I’m hallucinating here.
Maybe this is just my imagination.
It’s a side effect of the meditation we’re
doing, I don’t know.”
But, the instant this actually happened in
my head, the entity coming through the teacher
stopped talking to the class and turned to
me and said, “There’s an entity here for
you, now, if you’re ready to begin.”
And at the same moment, I glanced over and
noticed that one of the other classmates was
actually, had also, somehow, picked up on
this peripherally, what was going on, and
was actually sketching an image of Bashar
that I had seen in my head.
So I already had 2 external validations that
this wasn’t just going on inside me.
So for that reason I decided, “Ok, let’s
explore this and see what it’s all about.”
Ok.
So I went further in the class.
I did well enough that the teacher actually
asked me to co-channel the next class with
him.
And after that class, I was introduced to
a woman who was doing the first doctoral thesis
on the connection between psychology and channeling,
and I became one of her subjects and started
channeling at her house for her friends, while
she wrote notes to write her paper.
But the first week you know, it was like 5
friends, and then the second week was 20,
then the third week was 40.
And then we had to start doing it like twice
a week, and then renting auditoriums, and
then people would pass the recording around.
And before you know it, I was being invited
to different cities, different countries,
and it just took on a life of its own, and
here I am 30 years later.
Now I heard you say that you pretty much don’t
remember, or while it’s happening you’re
not very cognizant of what’s going on.
It’s like you’re off in some daydream
or something.
Yeah, I don’t hear the words so much.
It’s kind of like if you’re really lost
in a daydream, and somebody walks in the room
and tries to get your attention.
And they have to call your name 3 times before
you actually hear them?
Happens all the time with my wife [laughing].
Exactly!
So it’s like that.
It’s like the conversation might as well
be in the house next door; it’s so secondary
and so far away.
I’m paying attention to what I’m experiencing,
which is a lot of energy, a lot of imagery,
a lot of feeling, but I’m having my own
experience.
And whatever’s going on with the translation
in my brain, for the person sitting in front
of me, really in a sense is none of my business,
so I just don’t pay attention to it.
Hmm.
Seems that happens to different degrees with
different channels.
Like Edgar Cayce, as I understand it, was
really checked out, you k now?
Yes.
Some other channels, if their house was on
fire, you’d say, “Hey, your house is on
fire,” they’d get up and jump.
I don’t know, maybe you’re just wired
in different ways.
Yeah but I’ve also noticed in talked to
other channels, observing other channels,
I’ve noticed a progression, let’s say
generationally.
I think we, those who choose to channel in
this way, are becoming more and more involved.
So it’s like, I’m conscious, I know there’s
something going on, and I could probably stop
it if I wanted to, but I just don’t choose
to stop it.
But I’m more conscious and more aware than
I think like people like you’re mentioning,
like Edgar Cayce or Jane Roberts.
Because I think it’s important for the channel
to now know – at least to some degree – to
participate to some degree in what’s happening,
because the information coming through is
also to be applied to yourself as well as
to the people that you’re talking to.
So I think that you’re going to see more
and more and more involvement in a conscious
way.
And as I become, let’s say, more my own
version of Bashar, by just simply using the
information that he brings through, then I
can tap into my own higher mind, and I don’t
have to go into the altered state at all;
to bring a lot of the information through,
myself, at this point.
So I think that’s part of the idea, is that
we become more conscious, and still are capable
of tapping into that level of reality and
bringing through what we need.
Seems like some channelers, well you in particular,
you adopt a very different voice while you’re
doing it.
I do a pretty good imitation of it actually
[laughing]
Here’s the irony: I actually can’t imitate
that voice.
I have trouble imitating it, but something
that absolutely happens naturally.
The breathing that you hear happens naturally,
by going into the altered state.
The voice changes and the energy changes happen
just as a side effect of going into that state
and allowing his personality to be translated
through me.
One of the things – I don’t know, we can
touch on this later – but right now we’re
actually in the middle of…my other life
is [that] I’m in the film business.
And right now we’re making a documentary
about how I became a channel and who Bashar
is.
One of the things I’m most excited about
in this documentary is, I actually did a channeling
session with my head wired to an EEG machine.
So for the first time we’re actually going
to be able to demonstrate physically, what
are the differences going on in the human
brain in the normal waking state, and in the
channeling state.
And without giving a lot of stuff away right
now, I will definitely say people are going
to see, for the first time, that there are
profound differences between the two states.
And for the first time, I
think we’re going to be showing some scientific
evidence that this is truly, a real altered
state.
Not that anyone has to believe that Bashar
is real, but the channeling state is a true
altered state that we all actually have the
ability to get into, and that a lot of us
actually do get into from time to time, when
we’re in that zone, or doing what we love
to do - where we’re just doing it, we’re
not thinking about it, we don’t notice the
passage of time.
That’s a channeling state and we all do
that.
So for the first time, I think, the documentary
is actually going to show the scientific side
of what’s happing in the brain, in that
state.
So we’re really excited about that.
Yeah, it’s interesting.
And of course, a lot of that kind of research
has been done with meditation.
And they’ve identified that meditation evokes
a really distinct state that you can’t be…it’s
not just some minor modification of waking
state; it’s a major state, as waking, sleeping,
dreaming are distinct from one another.
Yes, there’s some similarities we discovered
to the meditation state, but there are also
some profound differences that are in addition
to the meditation state.
When you say we all channel from time to time,
perhaps without even knowing it, I’m wondering
if like…well like, you’re channeling someone
whom you say is actually a future version
of yourself – Bashar is some future version
of yourself.
Yes, that’s the way he presents himself.
And that’s something we can get into later
in more detail also, is time is not so linear
as we think, and we’ll get into that.
But then how about great geniuses like Mozart,
Beethoven, Einstein, do you think they were
channeling?
Yes.
They’re in the channeling state.
It’s really just expressing more of yourself,
more connectivity, more accessibility to knowledge
which exists throughout creation.
It’s just knowing that everything exists
in the moment and tapping into that present
moment so strongly, that you can bring through
what you need to bring through without really
thinking about it.
Yeah, and there’s the ancient idea of a
muse, you know, who inspires a great musician,
or artist, or something.
So do you think that these guys like Einstein
and so on, were just tapping into a deeper
aspect of their own creativity, or do you
think that some higher being or power said,
“Ok, it’s time for humanity to know about
relativity and here’s a good candidate.
This guy’s smart enough, let’s bring it
in through him”?
Well it could be both.
It could be both, and in a sense I feel it
has to be both.
Information permeates existence itself, and
whether another entity is involved in helping
deliver it, the person receiving it still
has to be on the right wavelength, still has
to be in the right state of being, or the
right vibrational frequency to receive it.
So I think it’s gotta be a two-way street.
You gotta be able to tap in and be open to
receiving whatever it is that’s available
to be received.
Whether someone is intentionally sending it
to you or not, or whether you’re reaching
out and getting it, to me is just sort of
an issue of what mechanism is being used,
but you still have to be in the right state
to be able to translate it through.
Not only the right state, but you also have
to have the right education.
I mean, Mozart knew about music and so therefore
he could channel all these beautiful things.
Einstein knew about mathematics and so on.
Exactly, but one of the things that I’ve
noticed in my life early on, and one of the
things that people often say when they hear
the channeling is that, I have, I guess [chuckling],
a relatively large vocabulary, so that Bashar
can really translate a lot of what he’s
saying into the necessary words.
And I noticed that in my life, growing up,
it was kind of one of the things that happened
for me automatically – my parents said that
I was reading magazines when I was a year
and a half old.
And English in school for me was never a problem.
I never understood why people could’t understand
punctuation, grammar, vocabulary, you know
– things like that.
And so I think it was now, in hindsight, I
needed to program myself with a large enough
vocabulary so that very esoteric concepts
and ideas could translate through me into
language we would understand.
And so yeah, I think there’s a lot of preparation
involved in these things, but a lot of times
it just happens in your life where you gravitate
to that thing, to give you the tools you need
to be able to function on that level, or translate
those concepts at some point in the future.
Yeah.
Yeah, and obviously you wouldn’t be a very
useful channel in Brazil or speaking in Afrikaans
of something [chuckling].
That Bashar, if he wanted to talk to those
people, is probably going to have to go through
somebody who speaks Portuguese, or something.
Yeah, because that’s a common misunderstanding
that people have about the idea of channeling.
Is, it’s not that it’s impossible for
an entity to sort of “override” the consciousness
of the channel’s programming and sometimes
by actually capable of pulling another language
through, but it’s really not what’s easiest
for the channel’s brain.
Because the channel has been programmed with
a particular language, and therefore yes,
you’re right, in some sense it’s easier
for the entity to actually go through a person
whose already programmed with a different
language.
And I’ve actually seen that happen with
Bashar.
At one point, many, many years ago, while
he was helping someone else learn how to channel;
he was acting as a mentor for them temporarily,
and allowing them to bring him through just
temporarily, until they could get a handle
on what channeling was and then channel their
own entity, he actually came through a woman
in Japan!
And therefore he was speaking through a female,
in Japanese, but it was still distinctly his
personality, his cadence, his style, his mannerisms.
So that was kind of a very odd thing for me
to experience, personally.
But yeah, most people have a misunderstanding
– because see he’s not speaking anything
at all; he’s just sending thoughts.
The thoughts are being translated by the biological
translator that we happen to be, and I’m
programmed with English, so that’s what
you get.
Yeah, how about on the dark side?
I mean, were guys like Hitler, Pol Pod, Idi
Amin, and Charles Manson channeling something?
Well [chuckling], I suppose you could say
they were channeling their negative egos,
or their fear-based egos.
But the idea of channeling is something that,
by definition integrative, and connective
and expansive.
And things that are perceived more negatively
are segregative and disconnective, and reductive
and destructive.
So the idea is not so much to say that they
might have been, quote on quote, “channeling”
in the sense of an integrated, positive, expanding,
mechanical concept, but that perhaps they
were experiencing so much disconnection and
fearbased belief systems, that they were simply
bringing through more and more of their own
negative ego, without actually really being
able to express a connection to a higher source.
Well I guess maybe to rephrase the question,
are there negative forces in the universe
who would like to use men like them, as means
or channels to bring about negative impacts
on humanity?
It’s possible.
You know, the universe is both positive and
negative, and I’m sure that there are entities
out there somewhere that don’t necessarily
have everyone’s best intention at heart,
but the thing I’m saying is, the person
has to already be kind of be gravitating towards
that wavelength to attract something like
that.
And the idea again is that, negative energy,
by definition, is segregative instead of connective,
so even though they might be aligning with
a negative entity, or a negative entity may
be aligning with someone on Earth that is
negatively oriented, there’s not much connection,
because connection by definition is positive.
So to align with something like that is probably
very difficult.
And I think when people talk about things
like
“possession,” you know, and “is a negative
entity taking over,” to me it’s really
simply more a matter of - in terms of speaking
of it as if it were physics – it’s more
a matter of the person, based on their own
negative belief systems, is putting themselves
in a negative vibrational frequency.
And by doing so, they may be emulating another
negative frequency that might have a similar
negative intention.
But it’s not like they can really be controlled
or possessed; it’s simply that for whatever
reason, their belief system is getting them
to agree to function on that same low vibration
or wavelength.
And so they’re emulating or mirroring what
another negative entity might also want to
do, but they’re doing it themselves.
They’re totally in control of that.
And if they change their mind about being
on that wavelength, they would sever that
experience in an instant, but their belief
system doesn’t allow them to do so.
Okay.
So you’re saying that a negative person
like Hitler, for instance, is not the polar
opposite of somebody who’s channeling a
lot of positivity and wisdom and knowledge,
and so on; he’s more mired in his egotism
and has just assumed some kind of role, and
has some kind of charismatic personality that
enables a lot of people to get all enthusiastic.
Yeah, it’s a fear-based belief system.
It’s a belief system based on limitation,
on lack, on fear – the negative definitions
that you’re somehow disconnected from Source.
And if you feel like you’re disconnected
from Source, then the ego sort of goes into
this negative space where it feels like it
has to now control everything, and manipulate
everything in order to feel the power that
it doesn’t allow itself to feel, because
it believes it’s disconnected.
People that feel connected to Source, that
know that they are connected – it’s not
that anyone can actually be disconnected,
but you can have a belief that you’re disconnected.
And if you believe you are, it’s like being
abandoned, it’s like being isolated.
Well, you’re going to try to do everything
in your power to try and find that connection
again.
But if you don’t understand that the power
is within you, you’re gonna assume that
it’s out there, and you’re going to manipulate
your reality and manipulate other people,
and force yourself on them in order to construct
a reality that you feel is making you feel
powerful or comfortable.
But really, anytime anyone forces something
on anyone else, it’s just a sign that they
don’t feel their power at all and they’re
trying to make up for it in some sort of artificial
way.
Great power, as Bashar said, really requires
the very gentlest touch.
So anytime anyone is forcing something on
anyone, what they’re actually saying is
that they don’t believe they have self-empowerment.
Just to belabor this point a little bit more,
from what I’m gathering, you would probably
say that what we see in terms of humanity
- all the dramas that have played out over
the hundreds and thousands of years – is
not necessarily a surface manifestation of
a tug-of-war between positive and negative
forces, sort of like Star Wars.
No.
The negative forces, at least in the examples
I’ve mentioned, are just the manifestations
of human ignorance and ego, but the positive
forces, you seem to be saying, could actually
be a channeling of some higher intelligences
which…?
Well what I’m saying is that, creation has
both positive and negative energy in it.
And so in that sense you can say, yes, there’s
both positive and negative forces, based on
what beings choose to align themselves with.
But what I’m saying is the expression of
positive or negative, has to do with what
an individual, based on their belief systems,
chooses to align with.
Sure.
So if they are in fear-based belief systems,
they’re going to align with a negative side
of reality and express it through themselves.
If they’re in positive-based belief systems,
they’re going to align with the positive
side of reality and express that.
So basically what I’m saying is that, it
still comes down to the fact that individuals
have a choice as to what to align with, and
it’s not necessarily even that the so-called
positive and negative forces, on a very basic
physics level, even necessarily have an agenda,
it’s just that this is what positive energy
is, this is what negative energy is.
And if you align with one or the other, you’re
going to express what is relevant and reflective
of that energy, through yourself.
So the real battle is really just taking place
within yourself, more than the idea that the
battle is taking place “out there” somewhere.
Because creation contains both sides, and
it’s not that it’s battling with itself,
but depending on what you lock into, the expression
of love, or the expression of fear, can be
personified through any particular individual,
based on what they align with.
Okay.
Yeah I mean, just in mythology and scriptural
accounts, especially in the East, there’s
so many accounts of the gods and demons battling
it out, you know.
Sure, sure, but I think that’s symbolic
of what’s going on within us.
It doesn’t mean that consciousness can’t
express itself archetypally in a seemingly
external, autonomous being – it can.
But I think that we only perceive that and
experience that when we’re on that vibrational
wavelength first.
Right, yeah, that’s good enough.
And we align ourselves with one or another’s
tendencies in creation according to our proclivities
– according to choice, according to our
makeup, and our karma, whatever.
Sure, sure.
So you’ll get the experience you’re on
the wavelength of.
So you know, anyone who’s in that fear-based
belief system is going to experience an archetypal,
autonomous, demonic reflection that – because
everything is conscious and made of consciousness,
of course will have its own consciousness,
and will present itself as an external entity
with this agenda.
But it’s actually activated by someone choosing
to be on that wavelength, and then seeing
the reality, and experiencing the reality
that they’re on the wavelength of.
Okay, good.
One other thing, just looping back a little
bit, I get the impression that some channelers
are very drained, and it even takes a toll
on their health to do it.
I think Jane Roberts might have been a case-in-point.
Whereas in your case, you’ve found it nothing
but energizing and enlivening, and it’s
enriched and enhanced your personal life as
Darryl.
Yes, yes, for the first couple of years it
was tiring.
But I think what happens is it takes a while
for a person to get used to the level of energy
that is coming through when you make a connection
like that, to a higher-plane entity.
And so at first there might be resistance
within the person and that resistance to that
energy is, I think, what causes the exhaustion.
But if you open up, eventually, ideally, I
think the idea is to relax and trust it, and
open up enough so that when you really let
that energy through without resistance, then
you find that it actually does start to sustain,
support and energize you.
So if people are only experiencing the idea
of exhaustion and being drained by it, that
might be an indication – I’m not going
to say in every case, because I can’t speak
for everyone, ‘cause everyone has their
own path, but – it might in general be an
indication, that perhaps more work needs to
be done internally, to let go of any negative
belief in there that might be causing a resistance
to that higher frequency.
And therefore, the channel working on themselves
a little more might ease the resistance to
that energy and allow them to experience it
in a much more positive and sustaining and
uplifting way.
And perhaps not even just belief, but neuro-physiological
wiring might need to be kind of rearranged
a bit before you can really do it without
obstruction.
Sure, well it goes hand in hand.
I think that anytime you change your belief
system you actually do change your neurological
wiring, and it becomes more reflective of
the fact you can handle more energy.
That’s one of the reasons again, why you
see me go into the altered state and you hear
the breathing and things like that change,
because I think you’re actually seeing a
physiological reflection of the different
neurological state that the body is going
into to be able to sustain that energy, without
causing a detriment to me.
Yeah.
You’re probably familiar with some people
who have been on television like Teresa Kaputo,
you know, the Long Island Medium and James
Von Prague, and 3 or 4 others.
Sure, and John Edwards…
John Edwards.
Do you consider what they are doing channeling?
‘Cause they don’t really seem to check
out at all; they seem to be all there and
they just say, “Oh, I’m just picking up
something here,” and “I’m talking to
your mother.”
Yes, yes, and that’s typically the form
of channeling that’s referred to as “mediumship.”
They’re acting as a conscious medium.
They’re sort of hearing or picking up on
symbols in their own consciousness that are
translations of what a spirit entity might
be sending, and they’re just translating
it through, to you, as a medium.
In a sense it is a form of channeling, just
maybe a different form of channeling.
But I think also they do represent what I
was saying earlier, as kind of where channeling
might be heading in general.
Because the idea is not necessarily TO check
out; the idea is to participate, but do so
in a way where you know you’re not, let’s
say, filtering or interfering with the information.
So I think we’re going to see more and more
examples of people remaining relatively conscious,
while at the same time developing the ability
to tap into those things, and still participate
while they’re delivering the information,
without really putting their own filters on
it.
So yeah, it’s a form of channeling.
And I guess you could say channeling is a
form of mediumship.
It’s just kind of different styles of the
same idea.
Might it be the case that if someone like
Teresa Kaputo is connecting with somebody’s
mother, that that entity – her mother – is
not so dissimilar from her or the people she’s
conveying it to, that she doesn’t really
have to go into a deep kind of disassociated
state?
Whereas if you’re channeling some kind of
alien from the future, maybe that life form
is so different, that you really, gotta, sort
of…
Maybe, maybe, I mean it could be the case
for me personally.
Again, based on maybe the belief system I
was raised in, it just might be easier for
me to go into a state that way, to allow something
that I consider to be so different to come
through more easily.
I don’t think it has to be done that way,
but that’s just maybe the way it works for
me.
Okay.
I bet you some people have asked you – and
I’ll ask you this in case it’s on some
people’s minds – when you first began
dealing with this stuff you thought, “Whoa,
what’s going on?”
And you began reading a lot of spiritual books,
and you probably immersed yourself and read
a ton of them – does Bashar say stuff that
you couldn’t have learned and didn’t learn
in reading?
I mean, does he surprise you with things he
comes out with, which you never even heard
of before and all of a sudden this thing is
coming out?
Yes, all the time.
There are people who have spoken to him who
are very well-trained psychologists, people
who have spoken to him who are physicists,
and they’ve walked away happy with the information
that he’s given them, that I wouldn’t
have a clue how to give them.
So yes, there are definitely perspectives,
ideas, concepts, that he’s come through
with that are beyond anything that I’ve
ever studied.
Yeah, that does happen.
Okay.
You eluded earlier to the fact that you say
[that] Bashar is actually a future you, in
the future!
How far in the future are we talking here?
Well, here’s where we get into some bizarre
temporal mechanics, because from Bashar’s
perspective everything really does exist at
the same time.
But he understands we’re perceiving things
a little more linearly, so he’s expressing
things in a more linear fashion.
In the way we think of time, he’s saying
that he would be considered about 300 years
in our future however, however, he’s also
saying that because he exists in a parallel
reality – another alternate dimension – his
reality vibrates - for lack of a better term
– 10 times faster than ours.
So evolutionarily, they’re actually 3,000
years ahead of us.
Oh I see.
… in their civilization.
But in terms of how we would relate to them,
in our linear sense, he says we would think
of them as about 300 years in the future.
Yeah.
Even if he weren’t you, there are civilizations,
I believe, that are functioning on different
levels or dimensions that we would consider
to be thousands of years ahead of ours.
Yes, absolutely.
I mean, does he ever tell you how things have
turned out?
What’s happening with the climate change?
Well, that’s when things get odd with temporal
mechanics.
Because he’s saying there’s no such thing
as a prediction of “the” future.
There are an infinite number of probable future
realities, and depending on the decisions
we make in the present, then it determines
which future probable reality we will choose
to experience.
But they all exist at the same time.
Now, he can sometimes look at the energy that
exists right now, which is basically what
he’s saying a prediction is - it’s not
a prediction of the future; it’s a sensing
of the energy that exists at the moment the
prediction is made – and if that energy
doesn’t change course, then it might have
a high degree of probability of coming to
pass.
If it does change course, then of course,
another probability will come up.
So, that’s always in fluctuation.
He has, from time to time on very rare occasions
said, “Alright, I’m sensing right now
that there’s something going on in your
collective society, that has so much energy
and so much momentum behind it, for one reason
or another, that it seems unlikely that it’s
going to change,” but this happens very
rarely and it has to have A LOT of energy
and A LOT of momentum behind it.
One of the ones I can point to is, I know
that there’s actually a recording that exists
that was made at a session, I think in 1998,
where he did say that somewhere around the
year 2001 there would be a terrorist attack
in New York City.
That came to pass.
So, the only reason that that was possible
to be made by him as a prediction is, for
some reason when he scanned all the probable
timelines, it seemed relatively inevitable
that we were heading down that path, somehow.
And so he felt it was unlikely to go into
any other probable future reality.
So that’s kind of how it works for them.
There are some other generalities that he
said, “Yes, I can see this has a high degree
of probability of coming to pass,” but he’ll
never say, “This is an absolute.”
Because once you actually let someone know
where the energy is going, we could decide
to change it.
So in a sense, a prediction can actually make
itself obsolete just by becoming known.
Yeah, and there’s all those sci-fi movies
about going back and changing something in
the past.
And you know, your parents aren’t born [chuckling]
as a result, and so that kind of thing.
Yeah, and from Bashar’s perspective it doesn’t
really work like that.
It’s more along the lines, I think now he’s
saying of, what physicists are saying when
they talk about the “many worlds” theory
– quantum mechanics.
Everything exists as a parallel reality and
you can’t actually go back in your own past.
You might shift over into a parallel reality
that LOOKS like your past, and meet a VERSION
of yourself that looks like your younger self,
but whatever it is you’re doing in that
reality is another reality and has nothing
to do with your timeline.
Hmm.
So would it be true to say, based on that
point, that you and I are living parallel
lives in other parallel universes, that are
similar to the ones we’re living, or a little
bit different in certain respects?
Yes, or very different.
It can run the entire gamut according to Bashar.
You can experience or perceive a parallel
reality version of yourself that is almost
indistinguishable from what you’re experiencing,
and you can perceive a parallel reality version
that’s so different you almost probably
wouldn’t recognize it…and everything in-between.
Hmm, interesting.
So maybe one parallel universe I’m just
wearing a different shirt, in another realm
I’m a professional baseball player or something.?
Right, and in another, you may be a different
life form altogether.
[phone ringing in background]
Interesting, okay, so before we lose the point
you were just talking about – sounds like
you’re saying that there are all these probabilities
and the future is malleable, the present is
malleable, and that there are certain probabilities
which have a lot more momentum behind them,
and others which are probably less probable.
Yes.
But it’s not cut in stone and it’s not
predetermined, and there is, you would say
I suppose, that we do have free will.
I mean, some spiritual teachers say that we
don’t have free will.
Well, I think it’s a combination.
I mean, you can look at it really, paradoxically,
from almost any point of view and be correct.
Bashar’s recently talked about the fact
that…okay, here’s one level of it: you
can say that linearly speaking, before this
life, your “soul” decided to experience
a certain thing, to explore a certain theme.
You could say that’s your destiny, you will
live this life.
Yeah, like you signed up to do the Bashar
thing.
Yeah, but how you do it, how you get there,
how you experience it, the way you go about
it, that’s up to your free will.
It’s up to what you prefer, how you feel
best doing it.
So it’s like saying well, you’ll walk
down this hallway - that you can’t avoid.
But you can run down the hall, you can walk
backwards, upside-down, left, right, slow,
fast, wearing this, wearing that, singing
a song, being upset – how you do it is your
free will, up to you, but you will walk down
that hallway.
So he’s saying from that perspective, there’s
a combination of the idea of destiny and free
will working hand in hand to create your experience.
On another level, he’s saying you could
look at it and say well, you are your destiny.
In this particular theme you can’t be anything
but you, therefore that’s your destiny.
How you choose to express who you are, again
can come into the idea of free will, but it’s
still always going to be YOU expressing that.
And therefore, you could say now you are fuzzing
the borders between free will and destiny,
because you can’t express yourself as anything
other than you, so now they become a little
more blended.
On the third level he’s saying, you could
also look at it as the idea of, well, let’s
say for example you come to a crossroads and
you go, “Well, I can have a choice of turning
left or I have a choice of turning right.”
Now you say, “Okay, my destiny is to come
to this crossroad, but my free will is to
choose to turn right or to choose to turn
left.”
Well, he’s also saying, well how do you
really know that?
You could choose right and how do you know
that wasn’t your destiny?
And then you could change your mind and say,
“No, no, no, I’m not going to go here,
I’m going to choose left,” well how do
you know that wasn’t your destiny?
So ultimately what he’s saying is, it’s
kind of a moot point, because from this level
you can’t really tell whether it’s free
will or destiny.
So it can be either, it can be both, and it
can be neither.
It’s really just about the experience that
you are, and that experience informs you,
and you do what you do.
And it almost doesn’t matter whether it’s
free will or destiny, because the ultimate
outcome is the same: you’re having an experience
that adds to the expansion of who and what
you are as a conscious being, and that’s
really the bottom line, and it doesn’t really
matter what mechanism you’re using – destiny
or free will – to achieve that.
Would it be true to say then that, we have
a certain destiny but most of us perceive
ourselves as having some wiggle room, some
latitude in which we can choose this or that,
and it may be that from some ultimate perspective
it is all predetermined, and there isn’t
any free will.
But as long as you PERCEIVE yourself as having
free will, then it’s not helpful to sort
of philosophically play with the notion that
it’s all predetermined, because you perceive
yourself as having free will and you’re
responsible to exercise it intelligently,
as best as you can.
Yes, and that’s the experience your’re
having.
See, I think what Bashar is actually saying
is, the structure of existence never changes;
that’s predetermined.
But your experience of the structure is what
changes, and that’s the idea of your free
will, is that you can experience the structure,
the destiny, from any perspective you want
to.
And as an experience, it’s real, but it
may not necessarily be representative of the
fact that the structure already exists and
never changes.
So you’re using a structure to create different
“real” experiences of that structure,
and it’s the experience that matters because
that’s what creates change, that’s what
creates growth, that’s what creates a difference
of perspective, whereas the structure never
changes.
So, it’s kind of both-in-one, and it’s
the experience that really matters; it’s
the process that’s the point.
Yeah, good.
At this point I want to interject a few questions
that people sent in.
They’re kind of related to what we’ve
been talking about.
One person asked, “I’d like to know if
Darryl activated his Merkaba,” – and you’re
going to have to define that, ‘cause I don’t
even know what it is [chuckling] – “before
he became a channel, after, or if it was always
activated?
Bashar comes to and through him to give channeled
information.
Does he ever travel to Bashar?
And if so, what happens?”
Is that all one question?
[laughing]
I guess that’s 2 questions from the same
person, so maybe the Merkaba one first.
Okay, a Merkaba, in general by a lot of people
is sort of considered an energy matrix, that
is representative of a certain state of alignment
that allows one to express more of your full
being into this reality.
How to answer that question?
I think looking at it from that perspective,
because in a sense a Merkaba is just a translation
of an idea, it’s a permission slip as Bashar
says, it’s a way of looking at a process.
Not necessarily an absolute description of
the structure of existence, but it may be
a way of interpreting the structure of creation
or existence.
And in that sense, yes, of course I think
the so-called configuration of my theme – if
you want to refer to that as a Merkaba – was
always there from birth, but certainly it
was activated by several incidents in my life.
And one of them of course - one of the strongest
ones - being the UFO incident itself, that
may have activated my ability to bring through
what was relevant to that particular matrix
or structure you’re calling a Merkaba.
I have had experiences with Bashar in dreamtime
directly.
The only thing I’ve ever experienced directly
in physical reality is his ship, twice –his
ship.
But I’ve had about four dream experiences
where I’ve either gone to his reality, or
we’ve had conversations all night long in
some sort of other alternate dimension that
I know are not just normal dreams, because
that’s all that’s happening, because I’m
talking to him like I’m talking to you right
now, and certain things happen in that dream
state that are very unusual.
So I guess in that sense, yes, you could say
there are times when I’ve gone to him, but
it usually happens when I’m asleep, at least
so far.
Okay, so that I’d say answered both questions.
So that ship you saw back in Los Angeles many
years ago, that was Bashar’s ship?
Yes.
Okay, and was it just sort of an interdimensional
kind of ship that came up from some other
dimension, or did it come from another physical
planet someplace that we can see through a
telescope?
Well, it can do both.
It can do both.
Does he have a home planet?
Yes, yes, they have a home planet, but like
I said, it’s in an alternate reality.
So we can’t actually see it unless we shift
to that dimension, in the same way that they
can’t really perceive our reality as physical
unless they shift into our dimension.
But if we were to overlap our reality with
their reality, his star system would be about
500 light years in the direction of the Orion
Constellation.
But again, it’s invisible to us unless we
shift into their physical reality.
But yes, they do have a home planet.
That’s interesting.
So the universe that we see through the Hubble
telescope or whatever, we’re just seeing
a layer of the cake, it’s just one dimension.
And if we had a telescope that could not only
see far away but could shift dimensions, we
would see whole different configurations of
stars and galaxies and planets on those other
dimensions...?
Yeah, in much the same way that here we have
a visible spectrum of light.
And we can’t really with our eyes perceive
infrared or ultraviolet light, but we have
instruments that can do that for us and allow
us to peer at something that our senses can’t
naturally pick up.
So yes, Bashar’s people have the ability
to do that naturally.
They’ve developed and evolved to the point
where they can perceive other dimensions with
their own actual senses, and that’s one
of the reasons why he can make connections
to his past self, which is me, because for
them, time and space is not as rigid or fixed
as it is at this point for us.
But we’re evolving to a point where we’re
gaining the same kind of flexibility that
his civilization already experiences.
You know how astrophysicists talk about that
maybe 96% of the apparent matter and energy
in the universe is invisible – dark energy,
dark matter – and they can’t account for
the way the universe behaves based upon what
we can see with our eyes; there’s all this
mass that somehow causes gravitational effects
–they call dark matter.
So is that mass actually related to these
other dimensions of the universe that you’re
just referring to?
Maybe, but what I’m actually referring to
is something that looks similar to our own
universal reality - perhaps with its own matter,
its own dark matter, its own dark energy - but
it’s just in a different vibrational state.
Perhaps a better analogy would be the idea
that Bashar often uses, which is like our
TV programs.
When you’re watching a particular program
on TV, you know there are hundreds of other
programs that are playing at the same time,
but you don’t perceive them because you’re
not on that channel.
But if you switch channels then you’re perceiving
a completely different program, in much the
same way as the program you were just watching,
but now you’re no longer perceiving the
one you were looking at before, but it’s
still going on, so it’s more like that.
Each is its own real reality, its own real
universe, but they’re on different frequencies
and so they interpenetrate and overlap, but
we only see the universe that we happen to
be tuned to.
Yeah, and all the channels that you’re getting
on your satellite dish or your cable, they’re
actually all coming in at once, and they’re
not conflicting with each other.
It’s just that your tuner is selecting a
particular one or another.
Right, so I think how dimensions function.
They’re all real, they’re all existing
at the same time, they’re all overlapping
all at once, but we have a very, very fine-tuned
frequency that is relevant for this particular
reality experience.
And we need to expand our ability and become
a broader spectrum antenna so to speak, before
we can really start picking up on these other
realities.
Now I think that we do that sometimes, from
time to time inadvertently, and this is where
people have experiences of other dimensions,
of another reality, the spirit realm, what
have you – is that sometimes our antenna
might get a little bit more broad-based for
one reason or another, and we start perceiving
things that are going on at the same time,
and we get kind of a double exposure of the
2 different, or 3 or 4 different realties
that do exist simultaneously.
So it does happen from time to time, but for
the most part, let’s say 99% of the time,
we’re focused in basically one particular
frequency of a reality, because that’s what
we wanted to experience.
And so would it be kind of simplistic or misguided
to try to map the topography of one reality
to another; to let’s say that if you could
shift to a different dimension, there might
be another planet between here and the moon,
or something, or are they really so much in
their own realms that it’s not sensible
or practical or meaningful to try to match
up or compare?
It depends.
It depends on whether or not that’s relevant
for the person doing that kind of exploration,
or that kind of research – it might be very
relevant for certain people.
And maybe this in some sense is what -to use
a general term - is what some shamans or enlightened
masters are able to do, is it’s more relevant
for them – they’ve made it more relevant
in their lives – to be able to perceive
things that in general, others don’t.
And therefore they can give you that…it’s
like: if you tune this way, you’ll see this.
This is what I’m seeing.
But it may not be relevant for everyone again,
because most people have a particular theme
they’re exploring and certain things may
not be completely relevant for them to explore
in that life.
But it may be very relevant for other people.
I have a few friends – several close friends
– who do perceive these other realities
routinely.
They see angels and stuff like that all the
time, and they see them attending to people.
Like you know, you might be at a restaurant
and see, okay, these subtle beings are attending
to that table or something.
So there does seem to be, in the case of those
beings, there does seem to be an interface
or interconnection between their reality and
ours, and they’re serving some function
in our reality.
Yeah, and I think this is happening more and
more.
I mean, I think this is actually part of what
this transformational age is all about.
We’re developing more ability to perceive
what we heretofore could not perceive, and
that’s a reflection of the expansion of
our consciousness.
And I think that’s one of the things that’s
going on in this age of transformation.
Good.
Here is another question that somebody else
sent in.
We kind of covered this but I think there’s
something new here: “Darryl has said that
Bashar is him in the future and Bashar lives
on another planet.
Does Darryl feel that he a starseed, in that
he usually carries out his incarnations on
other planets and comes to Earth for specific
tasks, at specific times?”
[silence pause] That’s the question [laughter].
You can pass some of these questions if you
feel like that’s okay.
No, well I suppose that I could say that from
a specific perspective, the answer to all
of that could be “yes,” but again because
Bashar has explained that time is not really
linear, that everything exists all at once,
I wouldn’t necessarily put it in the same
framework.
Let’s just say I know that like a lot of
people, there are probably incarnations going
on simultaneously in other civilizations that
I’m connected to.
There are probably other incarnations going
on on Earth in different timeframes, that
I’m connected to.
And some of those lives in both areas probably
serve certain functions that have to do with
the transformations going on here, on the
planet, and some of them probably don’t.
So I would say maybe the best answer is “all
of the above.”
Okay, good, there’s another one: “I’m
in a similar boat, or perhaps spaceship is
a better term,” someone wrote this, “I
found that experiencing life on different
dimensions, including knowing something about
the jobs I do elsewhere, has completely erased
any of the doubt about what happens after
we leave this incarnation, not to mention,
it puts this incarnation in perspective.”
That’s more of a statement than a question.
Yes, I would agree with it.
Some people – that works for some people.
Some people don’t need to do that, and I’m
not saying that one is better than the other.
It’s just again; it comes down to what theme
someone is exploring.
There are people that don’t want to know
anything about their connections to other
realities, other lives, what have you.
They get along just fine because they need
that focus, other people, it’s part of the
expansion to be aware of those things, and
I agree that it can put this experience in
a different perspective that can be very expanding
and very helpful for people.
So that is sort of the same spaceship that
I’m in, and so in that sense I
find a lot of familiarity with that statement,
sure.
Yeah, personally I find it very - even if
I’m not experiencing all that stuff – I
find it very gratifying to realize that there’s
far more to the universe than what meets our
mundane senses.
You know it’s thrilling, it’s exciting.
It is.
It’s a much bigger reality than we think.
Yeah, and perhaps it also roots out the tendency
to think, to say, “It’s only this.”
Whenever anyone uses the word “just” or
“only” about reality, you realize they’re
kind of locked into a ridged view.
Sure, yeah, and that’s okay if that’s
what they need, but there is more to it than
that.
There’s a line from The Incredible String
Band, whom you’re probably too young to
remember, but it was, “Whatever you think,
it’s more than that.”
[chuckling] I may be older than you think.
Can’t tell with that bald head, you know?
[laughing] Okay let’s shift a little bit
more.
We’ve sort of been weaving around here,
but let’s shift from the Darryl story to
the essence and some of the details of what
Bashar actually teaches.
If you had to sum it up in a nutshell, you
know, the elevator ride version of what Bashar
is actually here to convey, what would it
be?
Basically, the thing that I love about Bashar’s
information is, he takes a lot of [sound of
dog barking in background] metaphysical concepts
and he really – no pun intended – brings
them down to Earth, with very pragmatic and
practical understandings based on physics,
as to why they work.
And the one that I think is one of the most
important things, is he talks about what everyone
has now been hearing for years: follow your
passion, follow your bliss, act on your highest
excitement.
The reason why he says that is so critical
is because, the sensation that we experience
as passion, as excitement, as joy, as creativity,
as love, that sensation is your body’s physical
translation of the vibrational frequency of
your true, natural, core being.
And so anytime you act on something that contains
or expresses or reflects that energy of excitement,
that energy of passion, that energy of living-your-dreams
kind of idea, or bliss, you are in alignment
with who you truly are.
The thing, as he explains it, about excitement,
is that it is a complete kit.
And what he means by that is, excitement and
acting on it is the driving engine of your
life.
It is the organizing principle of your life,
it’s the path of least resistance in your
life, it’s the thread that leads to all
other expressions of your excitement, and
it’s the reflective mirror that points out
to you anything within your belief system
that might be out of alignment with your excitement,
so you can identify it, integrate it, and
bring it back into alignment with your excitement.
So the formula that he’s talking about when
he says, “Yes, act on your highest excitement,”
is fundamentally 3 parts: Act on your highest
excitement, to the BEST of your ability, without
any insistence or any assumption as to what
the outcome of that action ought to be.
Following that formula allows you to take
advantage of the fact that excitement is a
complete kit, and that it will bring you,
synchronistically, everything you need, at
the right place at the right time, to allow
you to continue to expand your experience
of living your excitement, and will support
you however you need to be supported.
But you must use the tool in the way the tool
was designed to be used, in order to get that
effect.
People are still, in many ways, “practicing”
the idea of really acting on your excitement
and what that means, because a lot of times
they will forget parts of the formula, parts
of the equation, such as letting go of what
the outcome needs to be.
And thus they are in this state where they
are learning what the physics of that idea
of following your bliss is all about, and
allowing their actions to really use that
tool in the most precise way possible.
But I can guarantee that when you do, because
I’ve experienced it myself over and over
again, it does work!
But you have to really use it precisely for
it to work.
But I like that Bashar is capable of explaining
WHY it works as an energy tool, and I think
that’s probably one of the most important
thing she has to say and has delivered to
us.
Hmm.
Jim Carrey gave the commencement address here
at the University in my town.
I saw that.
Did you see that, on YouTube or something?
It is very Bashar-like.
Oh cool.
Or Bashar is very Jim Carrey-like.
[laugter]
I think the idea really is that when you tap
into that understanding, truth is truth.
You get the idea, and just about everything
he expressed in that commencement speech was
very much in alignment with what Bashar has
been talking about for 30 years.
Yeah, he talked about how his father wanted
to be a comedian, I believe.
He said, but he chose a job as an accountant
so he could support his family.
And he ended up losing his job and the family
had to struggle.
And so Jim Carrey said, “You can fail at
what you don’t love, so you might as well
take a shot at what you love.”
Exactly!
Exactly, so why not?
Because at least you’ll be doing something
you love to do, you’ll be experiencing joy
and happiness no matter what happens, because
it is something that is more in alignment
with who you are.
And really, just by doing that, you haven’t
failed.
In some sense if you want to say there’s
any failure at all, it’s being something
that you’re not, or not being who you really
are, so why not take the leap?
Because it really isn’t an idea of a leap
of faith; it’s really knowing that this
is you, and getting the reflection that that’s
true.
And what would you say to a guy that, let’s
say, has a family and several kids and he’s
working a job that he doesn’t particularly
like, but he doesn’t have a lot of financial
buffer and he has to take care of his family,
and he really wants to be a professional musician,
but he hasn’t even begun to start moving
in that direction?
I mean, it could be very irresponsible for
him to just drop his job and become a musician.
Absolutely, and my response would be the same
as Bashar’s response.
And that is: as long as you’re holding on
to a belief system that says that your excitement
cannot support you as well as what it is that
you’re already doing, even if it’s not
what you love to do, you have to honor your
belief system.
Because it doesn’t serve you to jump off
a cliff if you don’t believe you have a
parachute.
[Chuckling] So by all means, you must hold
on to whatever belief system you BELIEVE you
need to hold on to, so you can feel comfortable
and safe and supported.
But what Bashar is encouraging us to do is,
at least you have the ability, sometime, to
start taking action on your excitement, to
the best of your ability, without any insistence
on what the outcome ought to look like.
And the more you are willing to at least take
some steps in that direction, the more you
are able to prove to yourself, eventually,
that your excitement can support you, and
that at whatever rate you are comfortable
changing, you can let go of the things you
don’t prefer to do, and only start doing
the things that you do prefer to do, and see
that those things can support you.
Maybe even better than the things that you
didn’t prefer to do!
But it does not do anyone any good to just
jump off that cliff if they don’t really
believe that there is a pillow down there
that they’re going to land on.
So honor your belief system, be honest with
yourself, really honest with yourself about
whether you believe your excitement can support
you or not.
Hold on to the things that will support you
until you know for a fact, for yourself, that
what you’re really truly all about is also
capable of supporting you, as I said, maybe
even better than what it is you’re doing
now that you don’t prefer.
But it’s gotta be a balancing act.
Yeah, and the transition doesn’t have to
be abrupt, necessarily.
It can be, but it doesn’t have to be.
Absolutely not.
And you might actually suck as a musician
[laughter] – you have delusions of grandeur,
you know?
Exactly, that’s where the honesty comes
in and you need to drop the expectation about
what you think is going to happen.
Because sometimes things that excite you don’t
necessarily excite you because the thing itself
has to come to fruition; sometimes you’re
lured by your excitement simply because you
need to move in that direction, and that’s
the only carrot that would get you moving.
Yeah, maybe something else will unfold.
Something else WILL unfold and may look absolutely
nothing like the thing that initially lured
you in that direction.
That’s why it’s important to be very open
about what the end result really needs to
be, because the physical mind doesn’t really
have the capacity to know how something actually
needs to happen.
Only the higher mind has that ability.
But the physical mind is designed to experience
what’s happening now, in the present.
And if you’re open to the idea that the
higher mind will bring you exactly what you
need in some way, shape, or form, even if
it looks nothing like you expected it to look,
if you go along with that and align with that,
you will see that whatever comes does actually
serve you, and does actually get you where
you need to go, even though it might be in
a completely unexpected route.
But that’s the surprise of life, is not
to be so rigid that you think you have all
the answers about how you’re going to get
somewhere, and let life show you, and let
your higher mind show you the truly unexpected
and surprising route that you actually will
take.
Look at myself for example.
If somebody had told me 30 years ago I was
going to wind up being a channel, and going
all around the world and channeling for thousands
of people, something that presents itself
as an extraterrestrial entity, I would have
said they’re completely out of their mind.
[Laughter] But just by following my excitement,
with no assumption how things were going to
turn out, I’ve had a pretty unusual life
and it’s brought me some pretty extraordinary
experiences that I wouldn’t necessarily
have had any other ways.
So you have to really leave yourself open
for those surprises because that’s the joy
of life, that’s the delight in life, is
to find something about yourself that you
didn’t even think was possible, can actually
happen.
Yes, it’s a great point.
In my own case, very often I’ve wanted and
expected and pushed to have things happen
in a particular way, and it’s not working
out, and what actually ends up happening is
far better than what I was trying for.
Exactly, exactly, the higher mind knows what’s
really best for you and what will really light
you up.
And when the physical mind insists that it
knows better, very often it falls quite short
of what your higher mind could actually bring
you, that could be many times, many times
more enjoyable than what you thought you could
ever attract.
Someone defined humility as “not insisting
that things happen in any particular way.”
Yeah.
There’s a great verse from the Bhagavad
Gita too.
It says, “You have control over action alone,
never over its fruits.
Live not for the fruits of action, nor attach
yourself to inaction.”
Exactly, it’s exactly what Bashar says.
When you act on the thing that excites you,
you have to act on that thing for its own
sake, not because of what you think its connected
to, not because of where you think it’ll
lead, not because of what you think it will
get you.
Because very often, doing what excites you
takes you down a very different path, but
that path will always truly be in the most
alignment with who you are, and it will allow
you to experience the most joy in your life.
Mm-hmm.
Here’s a note that I wrote down when I was
listening to one of your things.
It was, “Everything is God experiencing
Itself as everything.”
Wanna comment on that?
Mm-hm.
Yeah, I agree.
I mean it’s very similar, again, to what
Bashar said.
It’s like, we’re made of God, we’re
made of all that is.
There is nothing else but all that is.
And you can say, from a certain perspective,
that we are all the ways that God has of experiencing
itself, in all the ways that It can - all
the different perspectives, all the points
of view, all the kinds of experiences that
creation can have of Itself.
It doesn’t take away from what we are as
individual autonomous beings, but simultaneously,
we are all the different perspectives that
creation has of Itself.
So, I would agree with this statement.
Hmm, here’s another one: “Aligning with
the vibration of who you actually are…”
– let me tag a question onto that.
Would you say that each of us, all 7 billion
of us, ultimately, fundamentally, we’re
all the same person - we just referred to
that when we were talking about God – we’re
all the same thing.
But in terms of our individuality, would you
say that there’s a core, unique quality,
or entity or seed of what we actually are,
and we’re all aligned or misaligned to varying
degrees with that, and that life is really
all about getting aligned with that – with
that unique expression?
Yes.
In addition to the universal consciousness,
there’s also a sort of unique dharma or
individual channel or flow through one’s
life – the Tao for one’s own life that
needs to be attuned to?
Yes, I mean that’s the point of having the
experience.
It’s the theme that you’re exploring,
is rediscovering yourself from a different
point of view.
That’s in a sense why we forget who we are.
Because if we don’t forget who we are, we
can’t remember who we are from another point
of view.
We can’t rediscover ourselves in a unique
way if we retain all the knowledge of what
we are.
So we limit ourselves on purpose, in a sense,
in order to have a unique experience of rediscovering
ourselves in a new way.
And that’s what adds to the expansion of
creation - is that new perspective of ourselves,
that new discovery of who and what we truly
are.
Kind of a cosmic game of hide and seek.
Yeah, kinda, but we’re just playing it with
ourselves.
[Laughter]
A lot of the people listening to this show
usually focus on such concepts and terms such
as enlightenment, liberation, self-realization,
God-realization – that’s their whole orientation.
They don’t usually think much about UFOs
or entities form the future and all that,
but how does Bashar’s teaching segway with
that whole…?
Well, his teachings are all about enlightenment.
His teachings are all about understanding
and knowing the self - the true being, and
knowing that you are always connected to Source,
always connected to all that is, and that
what you’re experiencing is just a self-created
experience to rediscover yourself from a new
point of view.
To me that is enlightenment, so his teachings
are very much in alignment with that.
And you of all people should have realized
the self even more so than people to whom
you speak, since you live and breathe Bashar.
Maybe.
[laughter]
So what is your experience in terms of that
kind of thing; self-realization, enlightenment,
Godrealization?
Oh, it’s definitely changed my life profoundly.
I mean, I’m a very, very different person
today than if you knew me 30, 35 years ago.
I feel much more that I am the creator of
my reality, I feel much more transparent,
I feel much more in tune with existence itself.
I see the structure more transparently every
day -the underlying structure of existence
itself, and things become kind of -
I guess for lack of a better term – they
become kind of obvious.
It’s sort of like Bashar said one time,
if you’re holding a red rose and somebody
asks you what color the rose is, you say “red.”
Well, is that an opinion?
No, it’s an observation.
So many of the things that people look at
as opinions or theories, from Bashar’s perspective,
the information he’s delivering is not an
opinion; it’s actually an observation because
he can SEE the underlying structure of existence,
and that’s rubbed off on me more and more
and more, everyday.
So, certainly I feel that life is more joyful,
less effort is expended, things happen much
more synchronistically, much more magically
– if you want to use that word.
Sometimes the synchronicities that happen
are absolutely ridiculous, one thing after
another.
You’ll think of one thing and moments later,
suddenly you’ll get that thing, or see that
thing, or it will just appear with absolutely
no idea how it got there!
These things are really what the way life,
in a sense, can be, when you allow it to be
that way.
And I’m experiencing more and more and more
of that, everyday.
Of course, again, I was born here, I was raised
with similar belief systems to a lot of people,
similar limitations, but again, that’s MY
journey, is to transform those limitations
in ways that are reflective of who I
chose to be.
But I do feel that certainly after 30 years
of channeling Bashar, I’m doing that with
far more ease, and far more joy, and far more
understanding.
Cool.
In other words, you feel like you’re a work
in progress, to some extent?
Of course!
I certainly feel like everybody is.
If you’re breathing, you’re still evolving
[chuckling], or even if you’re not breathing.
Yeah absolutely, because you know, the idea
of progress and expansion still goes on even
on other levels, beyond this one.
And each level has its own idea of what that
expansion contains, what kind of experiences
are relevant to the idea of expansion.
But of course, I think everything is always
a work in progress.
I don’t think that really every ends.
But I have people who say to me, “Well if
you’re really awakened, then you’re settled
in some sort of ground state of existence
– some unbounded awareness, and you’re
just not seeking experiences anymore.
There’s just this sort of complete peace
and folding back into the self, from which
you have no inclination to emerge, to explore
different things here and there.”
I don’t know that I agree but I’m just
throwing that out, you know?
Yeah, well I think what we get caught in is
this idea of dichotomy; of things are either
this, or they’re that.
And really, from the perspective that Bashar
comes from, things are this and that.
So therefore yes, you can get into a state
of perfect peace, perfect bliss, perfect centeredness
AND, I would say that when you are in that
state, you actually start experiencing an
unbridled curiosity to explore even more.
[Rick chuckles] Because when you’re in that
state you become more aware that there IS
more to explore, and that exploration doesn’t
have to feel the same as it did from the other
level you were just in.
But I still don’t think it stops.
It may not feel like an effort anymore, but
I think that’s just because you become more
aligned with it.
It’s more representative of who you truly
are, and so you don’t feel the resistance
to it anymore, so there’s not as much difference
between you and what you’re exploring, but
I don’t think you stop exploring.
Because I think BECOMING is also the essence
of being; I think it’s one and the same
thing.
Hmm.
I think there’s actually a Zen saying which
is, “Always being, always becoming.”
That is the same thing.
It’s this, and that.
Being your true self is always becoming something
more, and becoming something more happens
more strongly from a state of centered beingness.
Very beautifully put.
It’s inspiring to hear you say that.
It resonates with…my orientation anyway.
And wouldn’t you say that established in
being, as we’ve been saying, further exploration
doesn’t imply that you’re lacking in fulfillment
and you need this, that, or the other thing
in order to complete yourself; it’s more
that, from a state of completion there is
plenty of icing to add to the cake, plenty
of interesting things yet to understand?
Sure, because you could, in a sense - and
I’ll use the word you used, “completion”
– in a sense you will never be complete,
but you can be complete in the idea you are
at that moment.
In other words, right now, you are the absolute
perfect version of whatever you are at this
moment.
That doesn’t mean you won’t become something
else.
And in that moment you’ll be the absolute
perfect version of whatever that is, that
doesn’t mean you won’t become something
else.
So one does not contradict the other, one
doesn’t exclude the other.
You can be absolutely centered and absolutely
perfect for whatever you are at this moment
of experiencing yourself, and it has absolutely
nothing to do with the fact that you can become
something else that will be equally perfect
for what it is in the next moment.
Yeah, and that way of putting it has an individual
connotation, but to put it slightly differently:
you are the absolute, you are the ground state
of the universe, but you are also an individual
expression.
And that individual expression has certain
capabilities, and certain proclivities and
inclinations, and those can be enjoyed and
exercised.
Yes, because that’s the point of the individual
perspective.
So it’s like yes, every individual being
is all that is, experiencing itself as a part
of all that is.
It’s one and the same, but it’s 2 different
perspectives on the spectrum.
Yeah, okay, good!
[Chuckling] Did that one.
[Laughing]
Moving on.
Here’s one: “Bashar was talking about
parallel realities during one of his talks,”
– and you and I have talked about it during
this interview – “is there a Hiroshima
on which the bomb didn’t drop?”
Of course.
Really?
Anything you can imagine, somewhere, somehow,
it’s playing out.
Now whether it’s in the same kind of reality
as ours, who’s to say?
But, Bashar has basically said, “You can’t
imagine nonexistence.
So anything that comes in your imagination
is part of creation, in some form or expression.”
So I would say that the example you just gave,
has got a higher degree of being more literal,
in the sense of another physical parallel
reality, because it’s so similar to the
one we’re experiencing, but sure.
I mean, science fiction has explored this
idea for a long time, where you’ve got things
that happen in one reality can have a completely
different history in another parallel reality,
and still seem to be a very similar kind of
Earth.
So yeah, absolutely, there are parallel realities
where that didn’t happen, parallel realities
where the Nazis won World War Two, parallel
realities where John Kennedy is still alive,
and all of the above.
Because there’s an infinite number of those
experiences so, sure.
Seems like they would diverge quite dramatically
over time, if certain things didn’t happen,
you know?
Yeah, right, exactly, so that’s the whole
point of having an infinite creation, is you
can experience every single possible variation
that there is to experience, and it is being
experienced by some aspect of all that is.
And just as real to them as we feel we are
real.
Okay, here’s another one sent in by somebody:
“Bashar talked about time and space in our
reality is created frame by frame,” and
I know this guy, he’s a friend of ours who
has computer expertise, so he says, “that
would take an unbelievably amount of computing
power, processing power, especially at very
high frame rates.”
[Laughter]
Well, yes but, we are that powerful.
Creation is that powerful, but at the same
time it’s also exceedingly economical.
In essence again, this is a case of not ‘this
or that,’ but ‘this and that.’
Yes, the idea that there are billions of frames
per second that are creating the illusion
of our movement and our physical reality,
and that time and space are side effects of
our consciousness shifting through those billions
of frames per second, like a projector light
projecting through different frames on a film
strip to project an ILLUSION of movement on
a screen, you could say yes, that’s one
way to look at how the idea of physical reality
is created.
At the same time, no pun intended, there is
only one moment in existence.
Everything is always now, but it’s the same
moment from a different perspective.
So in a sense it’s this, and it’s also
that.
So the fact that there’s only one moment
means that there doesn’t have to be an incredible
amount of computing power, because there really
is only one moment being looked at from a
number of different perspectives, at a very
high frame rate.
But the frame rate is a perspective of a particular
reality, so it creates the illusion of a need
for a lot of computing power, which may not
actually really be necessary.
But you’re looking at it from 2 different
perspectives, so you’re using the terminology
and the language of 2 different perspectives.
It’s true to say there’s a high degree
of frame rate and a high degree of computing
power from this perspective, but from the
other perspective, where there’s only a
single moment in existence, no computing power
is needed.
So it’s just again on that sliding scale
of how you want to look at the idea, that
determines the terminology and the process
that you believe is necessary to understand
that perspective, if that makes sense.
But yes, looking at it linearly Bashar has
said, “Time is a side effect of our consciousness
shifting through billions of parallel reality
frames per second, and that’s what creates
the illusion of time, space, movement, and
change.”
In fact, everything is just all happening
at once.
It’s all just one big frozen moment in which
everything exists holographically, but we
are capable of creating an experience of looking
at it from different perspectives in a linear
sequence.
But that’s just an illusionary perspective.
So we’re like movie projectors which take
the film that’s going in many frames through,
and turn it into an intelligible movie.
Yes, yes, and all frames exist at the same
time, as the projectionist knows.
So using the movie metaphor with a movie film
– in fact I watched a thing on CNN last
night about the Kennedy assassination.
And they took a prover film and you could
see frame by frame [speaking slowly] by frame
what was happening.
So if you take a single frame of this billions
of frames per second that you say is the nature
of our reality – I don’t know if this
is a meaningful question but – what would
that frame consist of?
It would consist of a potential that has no
experience and is timeless.
There is no experience, no change, no variation
in that; it’s a frozen snapshot.
Is it like trillions of atoms in my fingertip,
all with their electrons just poised at a
certain point, and then the next frame is
that the electrons have shifted slightly to
their next point?
You can look at it from an animation point
of view and you say that is true as well.
At the same time, you have to also realize
that the atoms you’re talking about are
also frames.
Because there really aren’t different atoms;
it’s all one thing expressing itself as
different atoms.
So it depends on the perspective you’re
looking at it from as to whether it looks
like millions of different atoms, or whether
it just looks like one concept of potentiality.
It’s really just about perspective.
And you can frame it, you can describe it
with any kind of terminology you want, as
long as you understand that that terminology
is just where you are on the sliding scale
of
‘everything exists now’ to ‘there’s
an infinite experience of time and space’.
It’s just different perspectives of the
same thing.
So yes, you can describe it the way you described
it and that’s perfectly valid, from “a”
point of view.
It doesn’t discount any other way of describing
it, on that timeline.
One other thing to throw into the mix here
and perhaps you can comment on it is that,
physicists tell us that we shouldn’t stop
at atoms in our analysis of the universe,
if we keep going deeper we get down to sub-atomic
particles, or get more and more to the point
where there’s nothing of any material nature.
And you know, if String Theory is correct
we eventually get down to these vibrating
strings, which are just potentialities with
no physical components whatsoever, and that’s
really what the universe is – is this nonphysical
field of potentiality, or it appears to be
physical….
Or even something more simple than that.
One of the things that Bashar has talked about
from his perspective – if you want to say,
it’s a simpler version than that – is
what he calls the “Prime Radiant.”
That’s how it translates into our language.
And basically he’s saying, alright, he still
needs to - for the purpose of the conversation
- talk about this as if it is either a wave
or a particle, so he’s clear about the fact
that he’s simply using analogous terms.
But what he’s describing is a thought experiment,
and basically he’s saying this - imagine
this, this isn’t necessarily, absolutely
representative of what the reality is, but
it’s an analogy that can help us.
So he’s saying, “If you imagine that there’s
only a single particle in an infinite void
of emptiness.
And there’s nothing else in that void, just
that single particle.
Well, there are no laws of physics here.
The particle is not beholdent to do anything,
because it’s just hanging in an infinite
void and there are no limitations on it.
So if there are no limitations on it, that
particle could actually move at infinite speed.
There’s no speed of light law going on here.
So if a particle can move at infinite speed,
that means it can actually be everywhere at
once, in that infinite void.
And that would create the illusion, by being
so fast that it can actually appear everywhere,
it would create the illusion that there are
a number of different particles, when in fact
it’s all the same particle appearing next
to itself, over and over again so quickly,
that you can’t tell it’s the same, single
particle.”
Bashar is basically saying that’s a better
analogy, and it actually is a physical analogy
of how we actually are all one.
Because he’s basically saying, if you want
to even think about it as a particle, you’re
actually all made out of the same, one particle.
Not the same KIND of particle; but literally,
the same, one particle, in the ultimate timesharing
framework.
Where every single particle in me, is literally
the same particle you are made of.
So that’s the way they choose to look at
it, as an analogy in the physics context,
in the quantum context, if you will.
I’ve actually heard physicists, as I understood
them, say that very same things too.
So it’s not like an unheard of notion.
Right.
I know you’ve talked about this in other
Bashar sessions, but we introduced this interview
talking about the fact that you saw spaceships.
And there are some people who say, “Oh,
that wouldn’t be possible because it’s,
you know, so many light years,” and “How
could they get here?”
and all that business, so maybe just dispel
that.
Yeah, I think that’s really kinda an idea
that’s on its way out at this point.
I think that there are even now physicists
who are coming up with an understanding, and
formulas [of] how there are ways around that
idea.
There are ways of contracting space, warping
space, and so on, that don’t violate the
speed of light, they just get around it.
Because space itself can actually expand at
any rate it wants to.
It’s not subject to the speed of light,
because light exists within that space.
But in a sense, the idea of space-time is
above and beyond that, so it really has no
limitation on it in terms of how fast it can
expand.
I think there are civilizations that have
learned this trick, and although Bashar, in
describing how their spaceships get here from
another dimension, or travel light years in
the blink of an eye, has actually expressed
a very unique and very different kind of understanding
about how that works.
He’s basically saying that we think of an
object as existing in a location.
His perspective is that location is actually
one of the variables of the object.
So in other words, if you have an object here,
and then it moves to here, this represents
two completely different, let’s say, vibrational
equations.
They may be very subtly different, but they’re
different.
If you could isolate the locational x, y,
z variable in the object here, and impose
on it, somehow, the locational variable of
here, then the object has to stop existing
here and just instantaneously start existing
here, without actually having travelled inbetween.
That’s how their spaceships work.
So if they’re in one location in their solar
system, and they simply impose upon the ship
and everyone in it an overwhelming energy
frequency, that is representative of the locational
variable in the equation of our solar system,
their ship just pops out of existence in their
system, and pops into existence in ours.
They haven’t violated the speed of light
because they actually haven’t travelled
in normal space-time; they just redefined
the locational variable.
Because again, if everything actually exists
all at once, then that means it exists, potentially,
everywhere at once.
So what they’re doing is they’re taking
advantage of redefining that variable, to
stop existing here, and just start existing
here.
That’s how their ships travel.
And again, I think a lot of physicists on
our planet are beginning to get the idea that
‘you can’t get there from here,’ or
‘you can’t get here from there,’ is
a very outmoded idea.
And we’re actually learning now, even in
our own science, that that is possible, and
how to do that.
Let’s say they’re 300 light years away,
so how did they know how to fine tune the
locational variables so precisely, that they
don’t accidentally end up manifesting in
the middle of the sun, or something like that
[Laughter].
Well, the basic idea is practice!
[Laughter]
Practice could be rather disastrous [Laughter].
Well yeah, they actually have had a long time
to get used to this idea, like any technology.
Bashar has actually, at one point I remember,
did talk about the fact that in the beginning,
when they were learning this technology, they
did lose people.
Like our airplanes you know - the Wright brothers
in the early days, a lot of airplanes crashed.
Exactly.
So they have had to have their tests and perfect
this technology for themselves, but they’ve
also had thousands of years to do that.
So at this point, it’s not impossible that
they still might go astray now and then, but
I think they’ve probably reduced that probability
to a very small fraction of a percentage,
at this time.
They understand how to chart the universe
as a series of vibrational equations, and
so basically now, I think it’s just relatively
formulaic for them to do this.
So if they wanted to chart a particular galaxy
which they hadn’t visited yet, they’d
have a way of charting that remotely, before
actually teleporting themselves to it?
Yeah, they can extrapolate from the map they
already have as to what the likely frequencies
are to be, over there.
At least to enough of a degree that they could
probably get close, then perhaps refine it
from that point forward.
A friend overheard me yesterday at the grocery
store, talking about the fact that I was going
to interview you, and he got very excited
and sent in a question here, that’s related
to the topic we’re talking about, which
is going to seem pretty far out to some people,
but whatever.
[Laughter] Take it or leave it.
He said, “I am already teleporting in my
sports car.”
In other words he says, I can jump 40 or 50
miles.
And I say, “You sure you’re not just spacing
out?”
But he said, “I’m wondering if there’s
a similarity in teleporting in a spaceship
as the Ya-Yey do?”- [Rick trying to pronounce
it correctly] whoever they are?
[Chuckling]
Yes, Yaya.
It’s another civilization Bashar has talked
about, but yes.
I would actually say yes, it’s identical.
If that is actually happening, it’s identical.
In fact, again based on what we were talking
about before, it’s actually what we’re
doing all the time when we even experience
any movement at all, because in a sense we’re
jumping from one frame to another.
There’s no intervening travelling, we’re
just jumping from one frame to another.
All that Bashar’s people are doing is doing
it over a larger number of frames.
So you don’t have any problem with believing
that he actually may be teleporting in his
sports car?
You knew people who actually do that sort
of thing?
I actually do know people who have done it.
It’s not something that happens regularly.
I’ve experienced it in my life once.
I know someone else who did experience it
more than once.
They were – let’s see, how can I describe
what happened to them?
They were in an apartment with a roommate.
They were standing in the bathroom brushing
their hair, in the mirror.
It was a small apartment.
There is no way to get from the bathroom to
the kitchen without going through the living
room.
The roommate was in the kitchen.
Walked into the living room and into the bathroom
to talk to her roommate.
When she got to the bathroom, the roommate
wasn’t there.
The roommate suddenly realized that they were
standing in front of the fridge, in the kitchen,
with the hairbrush in her hand, staring at
the fridge, wondering how she got into the
kitchen
[Rick chuckling].
And the roommate came back into the kitchen
and said, “How the hell did you get past
me and into the kitchen?”
She said, “I don’t know.”
So I know that’s one strong example where
there was corroboration, that the person actually
popped from the bathroom to the kitchen with
no intervening travelling.
I experienced this once in my life where I
was with a friend, up near San Francisco.
And they were supposed to meet me – pick
me up – and we were going to lunch in a
nearby small town.
Now neither of us knew anything about this
area.
I’d never been there before; she had never
been there before.
So when she came to the hotel, picked me up,
went to the front desk and said, “How do
we get to this town?”
The person at the front desk gave us very
simple, very direct instructions how to get
to this town to have lunch.
We followed the directions to a T, got to
the town, had lunch.
On the way back, we reversed the directions
and suddenly realized we were several miles
north of where we should be, and it didn’t
make any sense.
So we turned around, got back on, went back
to the hotel and said, “Now wait a minute.
How did that happen?”
So we followed the directions again to retrace
our steps to see what had happened, and we
realized that the person at the front desk
had given us the wrong directions.
There was absolutely no way we could have
followed those directions and gotten to that
town, but we did.
So in that instance we knew, by proving it
to ourselves, that somehow we had just believed
her directions so strongly, that it didn’t
matter that they were wrong, we still got
where we needed to be.
And the directions were just too simple to
have made a mistake; it was literally just
one off-ramp away.
So I had the experience myself of that whole
slippage of space and time, that is possible
when you’re in the proper altered state.
I’m sure that cynics, as we defined them
in the beginning, would feel that there were
a lot of alternative explanations for what
you just described, but I would encourage
cynics to keep an open mind.
Oh of course, but that’s why we were skeptical,
because we couldn’t believe that that had
actually happened.
That’s why we actually followed the directions
again, but we absolutely proved to ourselves
that there was no way we could have gotten
to the town by actually following her directions,
now that we knew the layout of the land.
It was only because we had no clue whether
her directions were right or wrong, that we
actually wound up getting to the town following
her directions.
But her directions were wrong, and it was
absolutely too simple to have made a mistake.
This fellow further asks, “I’m wondering
if the ability to teleport in a car, opens
an energy in the collective consciousness
of the planet, that will allow teleporting
of the Ya-yey here, in their spaceships?”
Yes, because anytime anyone exhibits any example
that stretches the boundaries of what we think
is possible, I think that adds something to
the collective energy that makes it more possible
for other people.
I think this is what people generally refer
to as the “100th monkey syndrome”.
So there is a collective consciousness, I
believe, and when you do something in that,
when you do break a barrier, I do think you
actually kind of set up, let’s say, an energetic
lubricant that makes it easier for people
to slide along that same path again, and again,
and again.
Yeah.
Another question he has: “Do you have any
more information about teleportation that
you have not put in your previous YouTube
posts?”
Anything new?
Um, no, it’s really just about state of
being.
It’s really about letting go of preconceptions.
It’s really about expanding your understanding
that you actually are already, in a sense,
everywhere all at once, and just sort of reidentifying
your perspective from another point of view.
Okay.
So, is Bashar an optimist?
[Laughter] I know there are a lot of dire
situations right now on the planet, and it
almost seems to be heating up.
You know, getting more and more dire.
And the heating up, literally with the global
warming thing, and also geez, I mean, what’s
going on in Syria and Iraq right now, and
all kinds of things.
I mean, he’s not…you say he’s an optimist
– yes, I could say he’s an optimist because
he’s always looking at how can this situation,
regardless of how it looks, deliver a positive
outcome for you, a positive point of view,
a positive experience?
He will always look at it from a positive
point of view.
At the same time, that doesn’t mean he’s
in denial about recognizing that many of these
situations have been created from a negative
point of view.
But just because he observes that we may have
created things from a negative perspective,
doesn’t mean we still can’t reverse them
and turn it around, and get a positive result
from this.
So, he’s encouraging us to redefine these
things in a positive way.
So, for example, he understands that there’s
a lot of struggle and strife, and war and
conflict, and so on, but he says, “Here’s
another way to look at it: you’re accelerating
these things on your planet, you’re bringing
more and more and more and more out into the
open, so that you can decide that you don’t
prefer this anymore.
You’re giving yourself more examples of
negativity to make yourselves so sick and
tired of it, that you finally start choosing
only positivity.”
So from his perspective, that’s a positive
way to look at the negativity we’ve created,
is we’re getting it all out on the table.
Where now able to see all in front of us,
and have a dialogue between all of us, “Is
this really the direction we want to go in?
Is this what we prefer?”
Yes or no?
And if it’s no, how can we do something
about it?
How can we really change this?
How can we make a difference in a positive
direction?
So, he’s basically saying that all the negativity
coming up, bubbling up to the surface now,
is us getting all our fears on the table,
really examining our fears, and finally deciding
to let those fears go, so we can actually
have a reality like we say we prefer to have.
So he’s looking at it as an opportunity
to be more in control, more responsible, more
self-empowered, and make decisions that are
more in alignment with who we really prefer
to be.
Okay.
This question is related to what you just
said and perhaps will bring out another flavor
of it: “Does Bashar concur with the notion
that the planet, as a conscious entity, Gaia,
is waking up, and all the beings on it are
waking up.
And that it’s kind of like when a dog wakes
up and starts scratching its fleas, and it
starts to get a little turbulent for the fleas?
You know, things were kind of peaceful when
the dog was asleep.
But now things are beginning to really shake…”
Sure, we’re shaking ourselves awake.
Yeah, there’s certain things which really
don’t belong on the planet, which need to
be somehow removed or purged, and the purging
process is not necessarily going to be smooth
for those who are committed to those things.
It may seem things are really getting crazy
but it’s actually something good happening,
if you zoom out to see a big enough picture.
Yes, and another way again, is to go back
to the idea of infinite parallel versions
of Earth.
Because Bashar is basically saying, “It’s
not that you’re changing the world you’re
on, it’s that you’re changing yourself,
and shifting to a parallel version of Earth
that is already more reflective of the change
you made within yourself.”
Ahhh!
So the people that are staying, let’s say,
locked into the idea of resistance and negativity,
are simply shifting to versions of Earth that
are more and more reflective of struggle,
strife and negativity, and may experience
disastrous transformations.
People that are shifting in a positive way
are more in alignment with themselves, are
going to experience themselves shifting to
versions of Earth that are already more reflective
of that idea.
And so the people, ultimately, who are no
longer vibrationally compatible with being
in alignment with yourself, may start to disappear
from our lives and vice versa, over time.
And as we shift to more and more and more
diverse versions of the Earth, that already
exist – it’s more like that - rather than
changing the world you’re on.
Because that version of Earth will always
exist, because everything always exists, it’s
just a matter of what neighborhood do you
want to live in.
What Earth do you want to live on, and changing
yourself so that you shift to a reality that
is more representative of that change within
you.
Yeah, I can see two interpretations of what
you just said.
One is that, one might be feeling undergoing
a spiritual awakening, upwelling of more bliss,
consciousness, all that, and might be feeling
like, “Wow, life is really getting good
for me,” and yet at the same time, all hell
could be breaking loose in various places
around the world.
The economies could be collapsing and so on,
but from one’s own perspective, life is
really getting quite heavenly.
That’s one interpretation.
Another is that, as we finish these lifetimes
in these bodies, are you saying that perhaps
people who are really attached to one version
of Earth will take rebirth in a version of
Earth that’s more in tune with their proclivities,
whereas those who are going the other way
will take birth in a different version, much
more positive, heavenly version?
Yes.
Okay.
And everything in-between.
Yeah, so there’s like any number of varieties
that one could choose to dwell on according
to which way you want to stir the boat.
An infinite number of experiences on an infinite
number of realities, it’s really what it
comes down to.
It’s: choose what works for you.
Do you yourself do some kind of spiritual
exercise other than channeling Bashar?
No, not so much, because the channeling process;
the experience of being in that altered state,
for me, is extremely intense, and extremely
capable of delivering a lot of information,
a lot of perspectives, a lot of concepts.
And I find that that’s really what works
for me.
Now I guess you could say that in making films,
that’s my way of expressing my excitement,
that’s my way of putting myself as myself,
into that state of acting on my bliss and
then expressing what Bashar is talking about
in my reality.
So I suppose you could say film-making is
my other way of being in the state of being
where I’m expressing these things in my
life, as the person that I am.
Does Bashar offer practices that other people
can do on a daily basis?
He does, he does, but he refers to all such
practices as “permission slips”.
Basically what he’s saying is: all tools,
all techniques, all rituals, all formats,
and all objects, are basically permission
slips that we’re using.
We’re attracting ourselves to these tools,
these techniques, these rituals, because they
happen to be in alignment with the belief
system that we have.
And for some reason in our belief system,
we believe we need to use this tool to give
ourselves permission to be more of who we
are.
It’s not that the permission slip itself
– the ritual, the practice, the object – is
really doing it; we’re doing it, but for
some reason, our belief system says we need
this thing in order to give ourselves permission
to be more of who we are.
And that’s fine.
But basically what that means is, any permission
slip can work!
They’re all valid.
If you think that religion is your permission
slip, that’s fine.
If you think Tarot cards is your permission
If you think crystals is your permission slip,
that’s fine.
If you think nothing is your permission slip,
But they’re all permission slips because
they’re all representative of what your
belief system is in alignment with that will
allow you to relax a limitation, and give
yourself permission to be more of who you
are.
So anything will work, and if you’re attracted
to it, you’re attracted to it for a reason.
It’s probably indicative of where you are
in your belief system and what ritual will
work best for you, at that moment, that’s
why you’re attracted to it.
And if you change your mind tomorrow and are
attracted to something else, that’s because
you’ve changed and now you’re attracted
to a different permission slip.
But ultimately the idea is to understand that
they are just permission slips, and you don’t
need any of them, to just give yourself permission
to be more of who you are.
It can just be a decision; that can be a sufficient
permission slip.
Yeah, so in a way that subtly dismissive of
the value of practices and techniques, but
at the same time it also endorses them, if
you feel attracted to them.
He’s not saying, “Well, go ahead and do
it if you feel attracted, but you really don’t
it.”
No.
No, no, no, he’s not dismissing it because
he’s valuing the belief system that believes
that that’s what will work, that that’s
the process, because again, the experience
and the process IS the point.
So it’s not dismissive, it’s just saying
it’s okay to use those things, because that’s
the process you’ve decided you require to
have this experience of yourself, and that’s
absolutely valid.
He’s just looking also at simultaneously,
at the underlying mechanism that creates that
experience.
So he’s revealing the simplicity of the
mechanism, without invalidating the experience,
and at the same time simply saying that, when
you achieve a higher level of understanding,
you realize, as part of your valid process,
that you don’t necessarily need that permission
slip anymore.
In the same way that as an adult, you don’t
need the same kind of things you needed as
a kid, but that doesn’t invalidate the fact
that you needed them as a kid.
It doesn’t dismiss them; it’s what got
you to where you are, to the point where you
realize you don’t need those things anymore.
Yeah, if you’re crossing a river in a boat,
[Darryl saying “Exactly” in the background]
you kind of need the boat when you’re in
the middle of the river, but when you get
to the other shore, the boat is not needed
anymore.
In fact, if you keep clinging to the boat,
you’re kind of not able to enjoy the shore,
right?
[Chuckling]
Yeah, so it’s not a dismissive thing; it’s
simply: right place, right time, this is what
you need now.
And then you get to a point where you don’t
need that anymore, BECAUSE this is how it
works.
Yeah, okay, that’s good.
So, we’ve been going on for almost two hours.
This is great.
I really appreciate this discussion.
[Chuckling] Time flies!
Yeah, is there anything else that you feel
is important that I haven’t thought to ask
you that, you know, you want people to hear?
You know the idea of what I do, like I said,
on my own as a film-maker.
Like I said, we’re in the middle now of
doing a Bashar documentary.
My production company, Zia Films, has done
another film called ‘Dearly Departed’,
which is an exploration of the idea of the
afterlife.
So this is what excites me, it’s what gives
me joy, gets me acting on my bliss, to my
highest ability.
And as an example in that sense, I would absolutely,
certainly encourage, at whatever rate you’re
comfortable with, everyone to act on their
highest joy, because it is exceedingly rewarding.
Yes there are going to be challenges, yes
absolutely there are going to be things that
might turn you inside out, but if you always
know that whatever is happening can be used
in a positive way and you always give it a
positive reason, from personal experience
in making the movies that we’ve made, I
can guarantee you that by staying in that
state, you will always get a positive outcome
that’s many times better than you imagined.
It just does always work that way.
So, in following my own bliss, I can definitely
say that Bashar’s principles do work when
you apply them.
And I would encourage everyone, to the best
of their ability to act on your highest dreams,
because that’s really what you’re all
about.
Will these movies be available in theaters?
On YouTube?
On Netflix?
‘Dearly Departed’ is now available on
Gaiam TV and through Fast Spring.
They can go to our
Ziafilms.com website and order ‘Dearly Departed’
if they’re interested in that.
Of course they can also go to Bashar.org to
order any of the recordings that have been
made of Bashar events.
We are planning to present the Bashar documentary,
which is called ‘First Contact’ to film
festivals, to see if we can actually get a
distributor to put it into theaters first,
before we go to DVD.
And Zia Films, as its own production company,
has many projects that we’re creating and
developing that will get out there, on TV
or theaters, or in some way, shape, or form.
But yes, they can find out what we’ve already
done on Ziafilms.com or Bashar.org.
And I’ll link to this stuff from your page
on BATGAP.com.
Okay, thank you.
So people won’t have to know how to spell
it or anything.
They can follow those links.
[Chuckling] Thank you.
The friend who was asking me about teleporting
in his car was also asking whether you do
private sessions - Bashar does private sessions
- that you can get together with people somehow,
either in person or over Skype, or whatever.
No, I only do them in person at this point
because the way my schedule is, in terms of
the film production.
But all of that information, as to how to
set up a private session, is just based on
availability on my schedule, and that can
all be found out through the Bashar.org website.
Okay, so they’d come to L.A. or wherever
you’re gonna be?
They would have to; they would have to be
in L.A. I actually don’t usually have time
when we go to other nearby cities to do private
sessions.
And because of my production schedule at the
moment, we’re not actually travelling to
cities that are farther away from L.A. than
I can fly up in the morning, do the session,
and fly back the same night.
At this point, film production is keeping
me as close to L.A. as possible.
But we are doing things in San Francisco,
we’re doing things in Orange County, we
sometimes go as far as perhaps Arizona.
So they can, again, find our schedule on Bashar.org,
where Bashar events will be, but private sessions
will need to be in Los Angeles, yes.
Do you mind my asking how much the private
sessions cost?
Private sessions are $300 for an hour, for
1, 2, or 3 people.
Okay, good.
When you do travel places, well…they’ll
get it all on Bashar[.org].
If they want to find out your schedule, if
you happen to be speaking in New York or something.
Yes, it’s all on the website.
Do you have some kind of newsletter people
can sign up for to be notified of things like
that?
Yes, again that’s all through the Bashar
website.
Good, well we’ll link to all that.
Well thanks, this has been great.
Yes, this has, it’s been fun.
Let me make a few concluding remarks of a
general nature, that I always make.
I’ve been speaking with Darryl Anka who
channels Bashar; you know that by now, [chuckling]
if you’ve been watching this.
And we’ll be linking to all his things - his
films, Bashar.org, anything else he wants
to have linked to - you’ll find it on his
page at BATGAP.com.
B-A-T-G-A-P.
So if you happen to be listening to this in
an audio file that someone sent you, or seeing
it on YouTube, if you go to BATGAP.com you’ll
find sort of a mothership of all these interviews
that I’ve been doing.
There are about 230 of them so far.
There’s a place there to sign up to be notified
by email every time a new one is posted.
There’s a discussion group that is set up
for each interview, specific to that interview.
There is a link to an audio podcast, so you
could subscribe on iTunes and listen to it
on an iPod, so some such device.
There is a donate button, which I appreciate
people clicking if they have the wherewithal.
That’s the sole means of support for this
whole enterprise.
Thanks again Darryl.
Thank you very much.
I really appreciate you having me on the show.
And thank you for the work you do, so that
information like this can get out to people.
I really appreciate that.
Yeah, next week I’ll be interviewing Richard
Lang, who is a protégé of Douglas Harding,
who had a teaching called “The Headless
Way”.
And I believe the week after that is Peter
Russell, a scientist who’s written all kinds
of great books that I’ve been a fan of over
the years.
So thanks for listening or watching and we’ll
see you next time.